TRISNA NADI SELAMET

Software Engineer [Back End Development]

Location: Bogor | No.Hp: +62812-9438-8977 | Email: nadi.selamet@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a passionate person who enjoys creativity, and an IT programmer with knowledge of programming languages. I also have projects I have worked on myself in internal cases and also less than a year in manufacturing and corporate companies.

EXPERIENCE

PT. Sinar Mas Multiartha, Tbk - Jakarta, Indonesia

Software Engineer Back End Development [Aug 2021 - Feb 2022]

- Development of back end systems business unit.
- Creation of data structures model database.
- Design function cleaning data and validation Rest API.
- Version control systems GIT or SVN knowledge and experience.
- Programming language java framework spring boot.

PT. Suryaraya Rubberindo Industries – Bogor, Indonesia.

Intern website application [Sept 2019 – Nov 2019]

- Starting from analysis and data collection with observation, and brainstorming.
- One of the campus requirements. Using file Json and RDBMS Postgresql.
- Programming language Javascript.

PT. Suryaraya Rubberindo Industries – Bogor, Indonesia

General Accounting [Mar 2015 - Dec 2020]

- Creation financial reports with vba macro.
- Creation Input accounting data into system with vba macro.
- Search engine completeness of documents related to financial transaction with function excel.
- Process in the preparation of internal and eksternal.

EDUCATION

MERCU BUANA UNIVERSITY (2016 - 2020)

Bachelor's degree 2016 - 2020 Informatics IPK 3.37

CERTIFICATION

Certification Full-Stack Development.

Certification Algorithm Basic.

Certification Database Basic.

TRAINING FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT

January 2021 - July 2021

Javascript

Github

Node Js

posgreSQL

React Js

LANGUAGE

OPERATING SYSTEM Windows 7, 8, 10

Indonesia: Active English : Passive

SKILLS

Node Js

MySQL

Microsoft Office

Javascript

PosgreSQL

LibreOffice

Java

Hbase

Portfolio: https://trisna-nadi-selamet.github.io/Portfolio/

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Project Name : Confidential Project

Company : PT Sinar Mas Multiartha,Tbk

Start Date : August 2021 End Date : March 2022

Project Desc

Develop rest API for business unit needs, where data management can be processed regularly and adjust data

Technological Skills:

Java Framework spring boot

RDBMS or DBMS:

PosgreSql, Hbase

Task Description:

- Development design function cleaning data and validation Rest API, on a data that will be processed to the server side or database.
- Support continuous improvement by investigating alternatives and presenting them for architectural review purposes.
- Identify bottlenecks and bugs, and design solutions to problem.
- Improvement for architectural status code.
- Able to create standard API documentation to be consumed in Front end.

Project Name: API Content Management System

Training : Cours-Net Indonesia Full Stack Development Javascript

Start Date : January 2021 End Date : July 2021

Project Desc

Monitoring dashboard system for blog, that relate to each other.

Technological Skills:

Javascript, Node Js.

RDBMS or DBMS:

PosgreSql, MySql

Task Description:

- Development design function Javascript, Node Js.
- Coding assigned programming language according to design, reusable, reliable, testable, efficient.
- Cretion fetch API and communication RestFull API.
- Perform database design for the purpose of needs, which can later be used according to the request.

Project Name : Confidential Project

Company : PT Suryaraya Rubberindo Industries

Start Date : March 2015 End Date : December 2020

Project Desc

Report for monitoring financial, Report data payment and Search engine completeness of documents related to financial transaction.

Technological Skills:

Microsoft Excel.

Tools:

VBA Macro and function microsoft excel.

Task Description:

- Creation function microsoft excel for report system financial payment.
- Analyze report prosses payment data the company.
- Data collection with observation, and brainstorming for system purposes.

Portfolio: https://trisna-nadi-selamet.github.io/Portfolio/